for those who don't know Nike just
dropped their own line of strength
equipment and I got to be honest it's
pretty sweet from free weights to weight
benches and power racks they've got just
about everything you need to fully kit
out your home gym so you know what we're
going to do today we're going to spend
some time breaking down all of their
gear kind of talk about the specs and
sort of how it Compares against the rest
of the market we got a lot to talk about
today so let's get right to
[Music]
it
what's up y'all it's Jake back in the
barbing garage gym and for today's video
we're going to be talking about Nike's
brand new line of strength gear now I
have not purchased everything yet but I
did go ahead and purchase some of the
free weights as you see right here so
I'm really excited to show you guys up
close you know all the details of these
products but we're also going to talk
about some of the other gear that I
don't have yet now before I do all of
that I just want to make sure you guys
know that we've reviewed a whole lot of
fitness equipment on Barb ben.com and we
have a best list for every category
imaginable so for example all you got to
do is search barbin best barbells that
article is going to pull right up for
you and you can find out for yourself
which ones we like the
[Music]
best now I'm going to be putting out
good amount of individual reviews over
all the gear that was just right here in
front of me but I want to start this
video off with with probably the most
sought after piece of equipment they're
going to have which is the barbells all
right so Nike released two different
barbells the Nike barbell and the Nike
coated premium barbell I have the coated
premium one right here in front of me
it's got a ceramic finish so it's going
to be you know really highly resistant
to rust and corrosion the Nike barbell
the only difference here is that it's
Chrome and black chrome that's it all
the specs everything else is the same so
these are both multi-purpose bars and
you're going to have four needle
bearings in the loading sleeves it's
going to create a pretty solid rate of
spin but remember I'm going to detail
all that later on down the road I've
been pretty impressed with it so far you
do have a medium neural right here with
the volcano style nuring so each
individual marking dips in like a
volcano does and you do have dual neural
markings right here for identical hand
placement so the international power
liing Federation is on the inside
International weightlifting Federation
is on the outside so that's pretty cool
too these are also pretty compatibly
priced compared to the rest of the
market so the 15 kg version of that
regular bar is going to be about 250 the
20 kg is about 285 only reason it's
cheaper is just because the coating
Chrome is not as resistant to rust and
corrosion as this ceramic will be so
that extra money is probably going to be
worth it whichever bar you purchase
they're both going to have 190,000 tinel
strength rating so that's strong enough
for you know some heavy lifts but it's
also going to have a pretty solid amount
of whip which is something that you want
with an explosive lift like a power
clean now this is a solid bar
considering this is Nike's first go at
it but but you know for me the only
drawback I have with it is just the
knurling right here now it's just a
little bit passive and it doesn't seem
to be cut as deep as plenty of other
barbells out there so I'm sure in the
long run you know it's going to be
improved you know their next version and
you know so on and so forth but just for
now that's something that you need to
you know keep in
[Music]
mind all right so on to the next I guess
second most sought after piece of
equipment it's probably going to be
these dumbbells right here they're
really nice obviously you have the
rubber coating right here it's got this
hex design I love hex dumbbells I'm able
to do my push-ups on the floor with them
it's just a really great thing you can
do burpees with them I think they're
Superior than rounded dumbbells okay so
these range from 5 lb to 100 lb price
point is a little steep honestly so I
have the 50 lb pair right here these go
for $95 a piece so at least you know
$200 or so for a pair the hundreds
they're going to be $185 a piece
compared to a company like Rogue you're
getting with Rogue you can get the
hundreds for I think $ 355 for a pair
right now so kind of expensive I was a
little bit surprised but they're pretty
sweet like I said the steel handle right
here is Chrome plated so it's got a
little bit of rust and Corrosion
Protection and then you've got a pretty
nice nerling right here honestly now the
actual handle is going to change as you
go up and weight so everything under 75
excuse me 70 lb it's going to have this
ergonomic shaped handle while the 70s to
100 lb dumbbells those are all going to
have a straight handle the knurling
pattern is the same though and obviously
don't have anything other than these
right here but I'm sure those are going
to be really nice I prefer a straight
handle so honestly it'd be kind of nice
if you could choose it cost a lot of
money for them to do that but that'd be
kind of cool now one thing that's kind
of you know jumping at me it's a little
bit Troublesome is that the weight
accuracy is listed as plusus 3 3% that's
a pretty big percentage most of the time
with companies you're going to see you
know 1% so you know whenever I do the
the full review of these I'm going to
have a scale and kind of weigh them out
and everything like that so definitely
be on the
lookout okay so let's talk about some
kettle bells now and honestly their
their kettle bells are pretty average
compared to the rest of the competition
right these are gravity cast so there's
no welding right here which that's
something that you definitely want
that's a good thing powder coat finish
feels pretty good gives you a really
solid grip it's got a machine finished
flat base right here you don't have to
worry about it you wobbling over or
anything like that the thing that really
suuck out the most with me was the
actual packaging whenever I received
this kettle bell okay so if you've ever
bought a kettle bell before you know
that most of the time they're just in a
simple cardboard box and by the time you
get it that box has been kind of
destroyed and you're going to notice you
know some chips in the paint and that's
kind of annoying sometimes there's still
a chip right here I'm going to show you
in a second but I was actually you know
impressed by the effort that they took
to actually protect the kettle Bill all
right so is in that same you know normal
cardboard box that was inside of a
cardboard box that had styrofoam around
it and outside of the big cardboard box
was more cardboard so they really tried
to do their best effort to protect this
kettle bell as much as possible but as
you see there's a pretty big chunk right
here missing even a little bit right
here as well well so I wouldn't really
put that against Nike I think it's more
so just you know happened during Transit
somebody wasn't very careful with it but
you know I think that's pretty cool and
hopefully we kind of see that become a
common Trend common theme whatever you
want to call it within the fitness
industry now these are available from 9
lb up to 88 lbs I have the 53 lb bill
right here it's going to cost you about
a 100 bucks that's a pretty sweet deal
honestly I mean I I was just comparing
to kettle bell Kings and their 53lb Bell
is going to cost you about 166 bucks
right now so if you are in the market
for some new kettle bells I think these
are going to be pretty solid one more
thing that's kind of alarming similar to
the dumbbells is the fact that these
also have a plusus 3% weight accuracy
and you know whenever I do you know this
full review I'm also going to pull out a
scale and you know test it out and check
it out and everything like that so
that's definitely something that you
want to be you know cautious of because
you don't want to be you know swinging
around a dumbbell that's either heavier
or you not as heavy as
listed
okay so Nike also drops two different
style of bumper plates so they have your
you know regular you know virgin rubber
plates but they also have the crumb
bumpers right here these are technically
called The Grind bumpers I had to get
these dude these look just sweet in my
opinion they're made from recycled shoe
material so the rubber from shoes you
know manufacturing defects whatever the
the case is that's where they're coming
up with these right here and that's the
case with all crumb bumpers if you don't
know made with recycled Rubber and they
offer more balance than virgin rubber
plates do so with the other ones they
have a 88 durometer rating which is
going to lead to a dead bounce don't
know the rating of these but they're
pretty bouncy and I've noticed that in
my time with them once again I'm going
to do these you know in a full
individual review and we'll talk about
it more then but these are available at
a pretty solid price point so a pair of
these 45s right here about 110 bucks
it's cheaper than some other companies
out there actually 10 bucks more
expensive actually than the Virgin
rubber ones which is kind of surprising
and that means that the other ones are
also available at a really solid price
point 100 bucks for a pair of 45lb
bumper plates is kind of rare and I
think that's definitely something you
should go and snag if you're looking for
some new ones now these are thicker than
the other ones these are 3.15 in while
the Virgin rubber coating it's 2.98 with
the 45s so that extra thickness you know
it takes away from the amount of space
that's on your loading sleeve also you
know over time as you go up and waight
could affect the whip of your Baro a
little bit so just kind of keep that in
[Music]
mind so they also dropped two different
weight benches now they're both flat so
there's obviously not not a whole lot of
Versatility going on I really wish they
would have made an adjustable bench
maybe they will before too long who
knows but either way I mean both of them
are made from 11 gauge steel so they
both have an 1100 lb weight capacity but
if it was me I'd definitely go after the
one that has a handle and wheels it's
more practical overall but also that
front foot design is actually a tripod
so you're able to get better foot
placement as you go to lift plus it's
only 85 bucks more than the other one
and it has 3x3 inch steel tubing as
opposed to 2x two only thing here though
is that the bench does not meet the ipf
height requirements it's 18 in tall as
opposed to 17 so just keep that in
[Music]
mind
now I just want to briefly touch on
their squat racks and power racks as
well so they're actually calling it a
squat cage but to be honest it's a power
rack and I think that's awesome it's
ultimate versatility as opposed to the
squat stand and the squat rack so that
squat stands about 450 bucks the squat
rack is about 700 to 750 and then that
power rack that's going to cost you
about 950 bucks yeah I know that's more
expensive than the other ones but like I
said it's more versatile it's got a
pullup bar buil built into it and
everything like that they're using 3x3
in 11 gauge steel tubing on all of these
so that's amazing you know it's going to
be really durable and last you a long
time but they're also all going to have
an 1100 lb weight capacity so even you
know the most elite level lifters are
going to be able to easily you know work
out with these racks and that's going to
be great and it's just I I really I'm
really happy that Nike is also doing
that as opposed to just sticking to the
free
weights all right that's a wrap on
today's overview of Nike's new Strength
equipment this is a really great thing
for the fitness industry okay so because
of Nike's resources and everything
they're able to kind of lower their
price tags compared to some other
companies while not necessarily
sacrificing quality so hopefully this
leads to more competition within the
industry and more companies are able to
kind of step up their game a little bit
and drop the prices for the consumer
because let's be honest fitness
equipment is pretty expensive now
overall I've been pretty impressed with
the weights you see right here in front
of me just remember I am going to be
doing individual review for every single
one of these so stay on the lookout for
that thanks for hanging out with me
y'all hope this video was helpful and I
was kind of able to give you that brief
overview that you're looking for as
you're going to you know make any of
these purchases you can always purchase
it from the Nike strength website but
also head over to your local Dick
Sporting Goods you can snag all of it
right there as well now I'm going to go
keep testing all this gear I'll catch
you'all next
time
[Music]
n